流浪神差
あなたにご縁が有らんことを
夜ト様 あれやってください
Yato-sama!
Please, do your thing!
May our fates intertwine.
ひと仕事終えた後のワンカップは格別だな
夜ト様 信者たちをご覧下さい
ほら 夜トラーがあんなに
Nothing beats a fine cup of sake after a long day of work!
ついに時代が俺に追いついてしまったか
Look at all your worshippers, Yato-sama!
野望が叶うというのも 虚しいものだな
Isn't it amazing? Yatoites as far as the eye can see!
トップに立ったものにしか分からない この孤独
At last, the world has come to its senses.
心が寒い
May our fates interwine
And yet, having your ambition fulfilled feels quite empty.
夜ト様
May our fates interwine
誰か俺のガラスのハートを温めてほしい
Only someone who stands at the very top can understand this loneliness!
May our fates interwine
でしたら 私が
いえ 私が
It chills my heart.
私が 私が…
Yato-sama...
Oh, won't someone warm my frozen heart?
Oh, allow me!
焦らない 焦らない
No, me!
皆 俺のマイハニー
Me!
さあ
うるせー
わーい
Oh, settle down! Settle down!
There's plenty of me to go around.
Shut up already!
弾丸込めた小銃を　僕は片手に持っている
Noragami
震えた君のいる場所へ　足を早め向かっている
チクタク　針はチクタクと
dangan kometa shoujuu wo boku wa katate ni motte iru
With a loaded rifle in one hand
チクタク　針はチクタクと
dangan kometa shoujuu wo boku wa katate ni motte iru
With a loaded rifle in one hand
チクタク　針はチクタクと
dangan kometa shoujuu wo boku wa katate ni motte iru
With a loaded rifle in one hand
チクタク　針はチクタクと
dangan kometa shoujuu wo boku wa katate ni motte iru
With a loaded rifle in one hand
チクタク　針はチクタクと
dangan kometa shoujuu wo boku wa katate ni motte iru
With a loaded rifle in one hand
チクタク　針はチクタクと
dangan kometa shoujuu wo boku wa katate ni motte iru
With a loaded rifle in one hand
焦る心を急かしただけ
dangan kometa shoujuu wo boku wa katate ni motte iru
With a loaded rifle in one hand
furueta kimi no iru basho e ashi wo hayame mukatte iru
I rush to where you stand trembling
チクタク　針はチクタクと
furueta kimi no iru basho e ashi wo hayame mukatte iru
I rush to where you stand trembling
チクタク　針はチクタクと
furueta kimi no iru basho e ashi wo hayame mukatte iru
I rush to where you stand trembling
チクタク　針はチクタクと
furueta kimi no iru basho e ashi wo hayame mukatte iru
I rush to where you stand trembling
チクタク　針はチクタクと
furueta kimi no iru basho e ashi wo hayame mukatte iru
I rush to where you stand trembling
チクタク　針はチクタクと
furueta kimi no iru basho e ashi wo hayame mukatte iru
I rush to where you stand trembling
チクタク　針はチクタクと
furueta kimi no iru basho e ashi wo hayame mukatte iru
I rush to where you stand trembling
留まる気配もなく　進んでいく
chikutaku hari wa chikutaku to
chi
ku
ta
ha
ri
wa
chi
ku
ta
to
The clock is ticking
チクタク　針はチクタクと
aseru kokoro wo sekashita dake
Making my heart race even faster
終わりと始まりの境目
チクタク　針はチクタクと
chikutaku hari wo chikutaku to
chi
ku
ta
ha
ri
wo
chi
ku
ta
to
The clock is ticking
チクタク　針はチクタクと
todomaru kehai mo naku susunde yuku
Going on and on endlessly
全て重なった
閉口して　僕は待っていた
chikutaku hari wa chikutaku to
chi
ku
ta
ha
ri
wa
chi
ku
ta
to
The clock is ticking
薄暗い部屋　一人きり
In the small gap between end and beginning
owari to hajimari no sakaime
薄暗い部屋　一人きり
閉口して　僕は待っていた
chikutaku hari wa chikutaku to
chi
ku
ta
ha
ri
wa
chi
ku
ta
to
The clock is ticking
閉口して　僕は待っていた
subete kasanatta
That's where everything will happen
ドアを蹴破る　その音を
Heikou shite boku wa matte ita
閉口して　僕は待っていた
I was waiting helplessly
Heikou shite boku wa matte ita
閉口して　僕は待っていた
usugurai heya hitorikiri
薄暗い部屋　一人きり
In this dark room all by myself
閉口して　僕は待っていた
Heikou shite boku wa matte ita
I was there waiting helplessly
閉口して　僕は待っていた
Heikou shite boku wa matte ita
I was there waiting helplessly
閉口して　僕は待っていた
もう怖れることはないよ
doa wo keyaburu sono oto wo
For the sound of the door being kicked in
もう怖れることはないよ
Heikou shite boku wa matte ita
I was there waiting helplessly
弾丸込めた小銃を持って
Heikou shite boku wa matte ita
I was there waiting helplessly
弾丸込めた小銃を持って
usugurai heya hitorikiri
In this dark room all by myself
固く閉ざされたドアを蹴破った
Heikou shite boku wa matte ita
I was there waiting helplessly
吸い付いた銃口が跳ねて
mou osoreru koto wa nai yo
There's nothing to fear now
昨日の僕を貫いた
mou osoreru koto wa nai yo
おやすみ　その絶望を受け取って
dangan kometa shoujuu wo motte
With a loaded rifle in hand
おやすみ　その絶望を受け取って
dan
gan
ko
me
ta
sho
u
ju
wo
mo
明日への僕は歩き始めた
tte
kataku tozasareta doa wo keyabutta
I kick down the locked door
明日への僕は歩き始めた
ka
ta
ku
to
za
sa
re
ta
do
a
wo
ke
ya
bu
tta
また今夜　待ち合わせよう
suitsuita juukou ga hanete
The gun recoils
また今夜　待ち合わせよう
su
i
tsu
また今夜　待ち合わせよう
i
ta
ju
u
ko
ga
ha
ne
kinou no boku wo tsuranuita
As I pierce through my past self
ki
no
u
bo
ku
wo
tsu
ra
nu
i
ta
oyasumi sono zetsubou wo uketotte
I accept the lingering despair
ashita e no boku wa arukihajimeta
And start walking toward the future
mata kon'ya machiawaseyou
ma
ta
ko
n'
ya
ma
chi
a
wa
se
you
Let's meet again tonight
本字幕由诸神字幕组(kamigami.org)制作，仅供交流学习，禁止用于任何商业用途
日听:小然&千夜  翻译:maki&迩祢  校对:木落&叶隐  时间轴:Gissa&久嘉  压制:久嘉
Fantastic!
Thanks, Hiyori!
Offering
サンキュー ひより
そのかわり 今度の今度の今度こそ
In exchange, I expect you to finally—finally—listen to my request!
私の願い聞いてくださいね
たこさんウインナーだ
It's shaped like an octopus!
Are you even listening?!
You're not, are you?!
聞いてます
聞いてないですよね
ったく
Ugh...
こっちは夜トのくだらない寝言がデカ過ぎて
I barely got any sleep thanks to all your stupid sleep-talking.
寝不足だっていうのに
Man, that was a great dream!
ホントいい夢だったな
Well, keep dreaming. There's no way "Yatoites" will ever exist.
夜トラーとか ありえないし
そんな恥ずかしい格好するくらいなら
I'd rather flee overseas than dress in something that humiliating.
私 国外逃亡します
大体 これがもてるはずねぇじゃん
No girl would ever think that's cool.
これ
What was that?!
Who in their right mind would want to shake your hand?
誰が握手なんかしたがるんだよ
Did you know? His hands are always sweaty as hell.
知ってる
こいつの手 超汗ばんでんだぜ
If that's what you think, I'll show you...
だったら 見せてやろうか
what a god is capable of.
神の本気を
Huh?
All of my dreams will come true.
夢で見たことは全て現実になる
Wanna know why?
なぜなら
'Cause I bought this!
これ買っちゃった
何その壺
Some random pot?!
街でおばちゃんに手相見てもらったら
A lady in town read my palm and said, "I'll sell this to you and only you!"
あなたにだけ特別にお売りしますって言われちゃって
毎日こうやって磨きながら
She said all I have to do is chant, "Happy-happy, cool-cool,"
ハッピー ハッピー モテモテって唱えればいいだけなんだって
every day while I rub it like this!
こもられてる
That was a scam!
And this will help me win lotteries if I
put it on the westmost wall of my room!
これは西に飾ると 宝くじが当たるんだって
このブレスは 夢のマイホームが建って
This bracelet will help me build my dream home,
and this will boost my test scores
and get me into my dream college!
こっちは 偏差値アップ 志望校合格
With all these, I'll be happy-happy, cool-cool in no...
これだけあれば
あっという間に ハッピー パッピー モテモテ
Hiyori!
ひより
Jungle Tornado!
ジャングル トルネード
ちゃんと働きなさい
How about you work for a change?!
It's not my fault.
仕方ないだろう
働きたくたって 依頼が来ねんだからさ
I wanna work, but no one's calling me for any jobs.
夜ト 言ってましたよね
You said gods and their Regalia share mind and body, right?
神と神器は一心同体だって
せっかく立派な神器に出会えたのに
I don't think this is how a god should act,
especially after finding such a great Regalia.
神様のほうはそんなんで どうするんです
You need to pull yourself together, for both you and Yukine.
ちゃんとしてください 雪音君のためにも
Hiyori, go get your body.
ひより 体取って来い
Huh?
お前に合わせたい奴がいる
There's someone I want you to meet.
Chapter 4
Where Happiness Lies
ここは
Is this the place?
小福
Kofuku!
You here, Kofuku?!
いるか 小福
Yato-chan!
夜トちゃん
Man! Long time, no see!
久しぶりだな
Wow! I missed you, Yato-chan!
夜トちゃん 会いたかったよ
Wh-Who's she?
だ　誰だあいつ
I missed you too!
俺も
あのオーラからすると ひょっとして
Judging from that vibe... Could that be his...
No, there's no way.
いや でもそんなはずは
That's right, this is Kofuku...
こいつは小福
俺のか～の～じょ
my girlfriend!
I'm his girlfriend, Kofuku!
Nice to meet you!
彼女の小福です よろしく
Girlfriend?!
彼女
マジか
Are you serious?!
Anyway, Kofuku, I got a favor to ask.
でさあ 小福 頼みがあるんだ
Yes, Yato-chan?
な～に 夜トちゃん
Well, I recently turned this kid into a Regalia.
実は 最近ガキを神器にしてさ
でも俺 まだこんなだろう まだ
But... I still haven't caught a break yet, you know?
I'd really like to give him a nice, hot meal,
あいつに 温かい飯を食わせてやりたいのに
今は 雨風を忍ぶ場所すら与えてやれなくて
but I can't even provide decent shelter for him yet!
Oh, that's terrible to hear, Yato-chan!
夜トちゃん 大変だね
Don't worry! I'll help you out!
大丈夫 あたしがなんとかしてあげるよ
Will this be enough?
これで足りるかな
助かるぜ やっぱお前は最高にいいやつだな
You're a life-saver! A real sweetheart, seriously!
幸せ 夜トちゃんに褒められちゃった
Yato-chan praised me!
That just makes me so happy!
All right! Time to hit the casino!
っしゃあ パチンコでどっと稼ぐぜ
I'll come with you!
あたしも行く
ゲスの極みだな
He really is the bottom of the barrel.
おのれーーー
Son of a bitch!
You again?!
またお前か
Keep your hands off my lady!
俺のカミさんに手出すな
ふ 不倫
A-An affair?!
You hear me?!
聞いてんのか おのれ
いやぁ あたしのために争わないで
Oh my! Don't fight over little old me!
I'm Ebisu Kofuku's Regalia.
俺は 恵比寿小福の神器
名は黒（くろ） 器は黒（こく）
Base name's Kuro. As Regalia, Koku.
As a person, Daikoku.
呼び名が大黒だ
You're spilling it!
Awesome.
すっげー 恵比寿ったら有名人だよな
零してるよ
Ebisu's a real hotshot, isn't she?
Didn't I tell you to keep a hand on the lid?!
だから蓋を押せって
はーい
七福神の一人だよね
Yeah, she's one of the Seven Gods of Fortune.
Got it!
But she's nothing like the way she's portrayed.
でも イメージと全然違う
What are you talking about?
何を話してる
O-Oh, uh, just how cute of a couple you two are!
い いえ あの
とってもお似合いのご夫婦だなって
Couple?
夫婦
You're married, right?
ご結婚されてるんですよね
We aren't.
いや
Huh?! But earlier, you called Ebisu-san—
でも 先 恵比寿さんのこと
小福でいいよ
Just "Kofuku" is fine!
小福さんのこと カミさんって
You called Kofuku-san your lady.
俺の神様 神さんってことだ
No, it's kind of like calling her "milady." She's my goddess.
Right?
ね
Yup!
Oh, a standing tea twig! That's good luck!
茶柱が立った
ただのゴミだよ
That's just some leftover junk.
おかしいか
What, you got a problem?
I happen to like calling her that.
俺は気に入ってんだが
と とても素敵だと思います
I-I think it's very nice!
お前ら そいつと目合わすな
Don't look him in the eye, you guys.
Huh?!
You're putting yourselves at risk.
それ以上は危険だ
なぜなら そいつは
Because, despite his tough and intimidating appearance...
そんな極悪の面して
子供に興味がある
that guy is into kids!
Don't make it sound like I'm a bad guy!
誤解を招く言い方すんな
Don't worry! He's safe.
大丈夫だよ うちの大黒はね
My Daikoku just loves little kids so much.
ちっちゃい子見ると 視界から消えるまで
He likes sitting and staring at them until they vanish from sight!
うっとり眺めるくらい子供大好きなの
That doesn't make me sound safe at all.
今一気に大丈夫な人じゃなくなったぞ
Hey, boy.
おい そこの少年
びびんな そして隠すな
Calm down. And you don't need to hide him.
Are you Yato's Regalia? What's your name?
君 夜トの神器か
名前は
ゆ 雪音
Y-Yukine.
神器は長いの
Been a Regalia for a while now?
いや 初めて…です
No, not really. I just started.
まだ駆け出しで
I see.
そうか まだガキなのにな
And you're still just a kid, too...
Daikoku-san...
大黒…さん
Hey, hey!
ねえねえ
Y-Yes?!
はい
What about you?
あなたは
壱岐ひよりといいます
I'm Iki Hiyori.
Oh! So your name's Hiyorin!
ひよりんっていうんだ
"Rin"?
りん
You're a regular girl, Hiyorin.
What's your relationship with Yato-chan like?
ひよりんは 普通の子だね
夜トちゃんの何
Huh?! R-Relationship?!
な　何って
知りません あんな人
I don't care about that jerk!
Oh, come on!
やだ 何怒ってんの
Why are you so upset?!
Why? Tell me! Why?
なんで ねえ なんで
Sorry. My lady's a bit crazy.
ごめんな
うちの神さん バカなんだ
Are you a B-cup, Hiyorin?
ひよりん Bカップ
やめて　もう
Stop!
今日は新しい人と知り合えて かなり嬉しいようだな
Looks like she's happy that
she met someone new today.
んで どうだ 夜トんとこは
So, what's it like living with Yato?
だよな 待遇悪いもんな あそこ
Yeah, I thought so.
He's not much of a people person.
俺 転職したい
I want to get a different job!
いいんじゃねえ
Then get one!
Could I work here?!
ここは駄目
I'm all the help she needs.
ここは俺一人で十分だ
ですよね
Oh, right.
Oh, yeah! Yukki!
そうだ ユッキー
ユッキー
"Yukki"?
気をつけてね
You should be careful.
夜トちゃんのこと知ったの 悪い噂からだったもん
I first heard about Yato-chan through some nasty rumors.
Nasty rumors?
悪い噂
夜トちゃん ああ見えて怖～い神様なんだよ
Despite the way he looks and acts,
Yato-chan can actually be a terrifying god.
小福 ビビらせんなよ
Don't scare the kid, Kofuku.
Good news! I got called for a job!
グッドニュース 仕事の依頼だ
行くぞ 雪音
Let's go, Yukine!
ちょっと 置いていかないで
Wait! Don't just leave me behind!
お邪魔しました
Thank you for having us!
Aww!
You're leaving already, Hiyorin?
ひよりん もう行っちゃうの
夜ト 何故ここに二人を連れてきた
Yato...
Why'd you bring those two here?
Will
I'm sorry, Mom.
母さん ごめん
I hope you can forgive me.
先立つ不幸を
お電話ありがとうごさいます
Thanks for your call!
夜トでございます
Yato, at your service!
You knocked him off!
突き落とした
Oh, shoot!
嘘
Noragami
あれ 僕もう落ちてる
Huh? I'm already falling.
ホントに最後までついてないな
Man, I can't even get my own death right, huh?
Not so fast!
ちょっと待った
Do your daily doldrums have you down, miss?
奥さん 鬱屈した毎日に ため息ついてないですか
ご主人 会社と家庭の板挟み 辛いですね
Are you torn between work and family, sir?
Wanna teach some bullies a lesson, kiddies?
良い子の皆 仕返ししたいいじめっ子のお友達 いないかな
I can solve your problems in a jiffy!
そんなお悩み ズバッと解決いたします
Fast, affordable, and reliable!
速くて安くて安心　デリバリーゴッドの夜ト神
Delivery God Yato!
Yato
Call me anyti—
どうぞ　御ひいきに
Yato
ひより　てめえ
Damn it, Hiyori!
Skip the introduction and save him already!
そんな挨拶より　早くこの人助けて
Yato
It's handmade...
手作り
Yato
あ　ご挨拶遅れまして
Oh, pardon my late introduction. This is—I mean, was—my card.
私　こういうものでした
He's playing along?!
乗っかってきた
Ah, so you work—I mean, worked—at an ad agency?
ほう　浦澤さんは広告代理店の方でした
Section EC1
Marketing Group
ええ
Section EC1
Marketing Group
Yes.
Section EC1
Marketing Group
The company recently went bankrupt,
先日　会社が倒産しました
もう　どうしようもなくなってしまい
and this is the only option I had left.
Mom
Unknown Caller
最後に　田舎の親に謝りたかったんですが
Mom
Unknown Caller
I was trying to apologize to
my parents back home before I fell.
Mom
Unknown Caller
まさか　夜トさんに間違い電話してしまうなんて
Mom
Unknown Caller
Unfortunately, I accidentally called you instead.
Mom
Unknown Caller
ああ　あのワン切り営業
Ah, that telemarketing ploy—
No, I mean... This must be fate.
じゃなかった
これも何かのご縁です
とりあえずお話　お聞かせ願えますか
First, could you tell me how all this started?
Why don't you save him first?!
とりあえず助けませんか
昨年の冬のことでした
It happened last winter.
You're actually telling him?!
話すの
一人の少女と出会ったんです
I happened to meet a young girl.
不思議と目が離せませんでした
For whatever reason, I couldn't take my eyes off her.
何で私の顔
Why is it my face?!
ちょうどあなたぐらいの年恰好だったものですから　つい
Well, you kind of look like her.
You're right around the same age, too.
なるほど
Ah, I see. She was wearing stripes.
縞々だったのですね
見るな
Don't look!
家出少女だと思って
Thinking she might be a runaway,
I offered to take her to the police when...
警察に届けようとしたら
Sounds like you're hungry.
お腹空いてるんだ
交番に行く前に　何か食べる
Would you like to get something
to eat before we go to the station?
だめ
No.
外で食べちゃだめなの
I'm not allowed to go out to eat.
うちの人にきつく言われてるの
It's one of the rules I have to follow.
でも　たまに内緒で街に来ちゃうんだ
But sometimes, I sneak out
and come downtown anyway.
この子はとても厳しい家庭で育った子なんだと思いました
I could tell she had grown up in a very strict household.
This young girl wasn't even allowed outside. She was like a bird in a cage.
外も自由に歩けない
籠の中の鳥のような少女
ちょっと気分転換
You need a change of pace!
Where would you like to go?
何処に行きたい
こうして　僕らは付き合うことに
And that's how we started dating.
幸せな日々でした
Those were truly happy times.
You're a normalfag?!
リア充かよ
Police! This guy has illicit
sexual relations with runaways!
お巡りさん
家出少女を振り回しの不純異性交遊者です
It's not like that!
Our relationship is pure!
誤解です
僕らは清い関係です
We haven't done a single
indecent thing! I swear on my life!
やましいことは一切してない
嘘なら死んでもいい
That's not very convincing!
説得力ねえな
会える日は　何処にだって連れて行きました
Whenever we met, I took her wherever she wanted.
What do you think?
どう
似合うよ　とっても
It looks really nice on you.
Really?
そう
いいの　こんなに買って貰って
You really don't mind buying all these for me?
Well, they all looked good on you, so...
どれも似合ってたからね
ヤッべー　今月給料日まで持つかな
Crap. I hope I can last until this month's paycheck.
Thank you! I love you, Yusuke-kun!
ありがとう
裕介君　大好き
You're just bragging!
自慢か
Stop using my face!
だから私の顔やめて
Is it just me, or is this fall taking forever?
っつーか　落下長くね
これ　僕に？
For me?
It's my way of thanking you!
いつものお礼
カピパー　好きなんだ
Oh, you like Capypas?
Yup! I've never been to Capypa Land, though.
うん　でもカピパーランドは行ったことないんだ
あそこは夢と希望の王国だから
It's the "Kingdom of Dreams and Hopes," so I'm not allowed to go.
行っちゃだめって
What horrible parents!
なんて親だ
行こう
Let's visit Capypa Land!
カピパーランド
Really?!
本当？
その頃からです
It was around that time when things starting taking a turn for the worse.
少しずつ雲行きが怪しくなったのは
よしよし
There, there!
何故
Why?! Why are there middle-aged men wearing Capypa skins?!
何故おじさんたちはカピパーの生皮被ってるの
Did they kill Capypas?!
おじさんたちはカピパーを殺したの
They're just costumes... I mean, don't worry!
カピパーは着ぐる…
いや　大丈夫
A fairy used magic to make the Capypas all better!
カピパーたちは妖精さんが魔法で治してあげたよ
Forget the Capypas!
どうでもいいでしょ
デートに行くと　大抵こんな風についてなくて
Most of our dates suffered from similar bad luck.
釣られるように会社の業績もどんどん下がり
My performance at work steadily dropped.
ボーナスも出なくなり
I stopped getting bonuses,
and my meager savings dried up.
僅かな貯金も底をついてしまいました
Credit
cards
into
cash!
でも　彼女に頼られるのが嬉しくて
But I was just so happy to be there for her.
気が付けば
So, before I knew it...
Unknown caller
I know you're in there, Urasawa-san!
いるんだろ　おい
僕は完全に破産していました
I was completely bankrupt.
浦澤さん　出ていてくださいよ
Answer the door!
もっと一緒にいたい
I want to stay with her!
でも　このままじゃ
But as I am now, I'd only be a burden to her!
彼女にまで迷惑がかかる
彼女が学校を卒業したらプロポーズしようと思ってました
I was planning to propose to her after she graduated!
でも　僕にはもうその資格すらない
But there's no way I can do that now!
あの
Say, do you have a picture of this girl?
その彼女のシャメ　あります
Huh?
Why do you ask?
何
There's something about this story...
ちょっと心当たりが
This is her.
この子です
小福さん
Kofuku-san?!
えっ　何故彼女の名前を
Huh?! How do you know her name?!
やっぱりなぁ
I should have known.
What do you mean by that?!
やっぱりってどういうこと
あれ　言ってなかったっけ
Oh, I didn't tell you?
あいつは貧乏神だ
She's the god of poverty.
G-God of poverty?!
び　貧乏神
恵比寿小福は言わば源氏名
Ebisu Kofuku is her professional name; a pen name, if you will.
お仕事上のニックネームだ
Her real name would be bad for business, you know?
本名じゃ客が付くわけねえからな
悪いことは言わねぇ
Take my advice.
Just forget about that girl. Seriously.
マジであの女だけはやめとけ
Huh?
貧乏神は厄災しか起こせない
The god of poverty only brings disaster!
下げマン中の下げマン
She'll spoil any luck you have! She's the Luck-Killing Queen!
クイーン　オブ下げマンだ
さらに言っとくと
On top of that...
あの女にはおっかねー旦那がいる
She has a man in her life you don't wanna mess with.
しかも小福はああ見えて年増だ
Kofuku's no spring chicken, anyway.
She's way, way, way older than
your mom... or even your grandma.
お前の母ちゃん
いや　ばあちゃんよりも遥かに年上の大年増だぞ
よし　今から小福との縁を切る
All right! Now to sever your ties with Kofuku!
Huh?
Sever his ties?! But that means...
縁を切るって　切ったら
He'll forget everything relating to Kofuku.
小福に纏わるすべてを忘れる
え　いやだ
N-No! I don't want to forget her!
彼女を忘れるなんて　そんなこと絶対に嫌だ
Absolutely not!
If you don't cut your ties, you're gonna die, you know.
このまま縁を切らねえていうと
お前　本当に死ぬぞ
構わない
I don't care! I love her from the bottom of my heart!
僕は心から彼女を愛している
馬鹿ろう
You dumbass!
自ら死を選んだやつが
Someone who chooses to kill himself isn't cut out for love!
愛を貫き通せるか
Hurry up!
早くして
What is even happening here?
何この本気の茶番
All right! You're up, Yukine!
よし　雪音　お前の出番だ
Huh?
W-Wait! I've never severed someone's ties before!
ま　待ってよ
俺縁なんて切ったことないし
It's okay! I know you can do it!
大丈夫だ
お前ならできる
Have faith in me!
俺を信じろ
来い　雪器
Come, Sekki!
小福に何か伝えることは
Anything you want me to tell Kofuku?
小福ちゃん　お幸せに
"May you live a happy life, Kofuku-chan."
それだけです
That's all.
確かに聞き届けた
Your request has been heard loud and clear!
With my advent, I, the Yato god...
吾　夜ト神来たり下り
hereby sever your ties using Sekki!
この縁　雪器を以って断ち切らん
Sunder!
絶
1 contact deleted
何それ
Are you serious?
あたしが全部悪いの
That was all my fault?
Well, I did have a little fun with Yusuke, though!
確かに裕介君とはちょっと遊んだけど
A little?
ちょっと？
Kofuku! You did all this behind your Regalia's back?
小福
俺という神器がいながら
It's not my fault!
だってあそこ行っちゃだめ
I was sick of you telling me I can't go here or there or anywhere!
ここ行っちゃだめってうるさいんだもん
I told you that for a reason!
You spread disaster wherever you go!
あたりめえだ
厄災撒き散らすだろうが
Sheesh...
やれやれ
しかしお前　やるじゃねえか
Anyway, you got some skills, kid!
新人のくせに　縁切りなんて
A rookie like you, severing someone's ties...
Oh? Is it that big of a deal?
そんなすごいことなの
ああ　縁は結ぶより切るほうが難しい
Yeah. Severing a bond is
much harder than making one.
神器の能力にも大いに左右されるしな
A Regalia's abilities are a big part of it, too.
別にどってことなかったけど
I thought it was a piece of cake, though.
頼もしいな
That's good to hear!
夜ト　いい神器が見つかったじゃないか
Looks like you've found
yourself a good Regalia, Yato.
I know, right?! There's a reason I fell for him at first sight!
でしょう
何だって 俺が見初めたやつだから
Right, Yukine-kun?!
ねぇ　雪音君
キモっ　離せ
Gross! Let go!
Don't be shy!
照れるなよう~よう
G-Get off me!
や　やめろ
Sorry about everything.
This is for your trouble.
悪かったな
これ　今回の迷惑料ね
毎度有り
Pleasure doing business!
じゃあ
Later!
バイバイ
Bye-bye!
Let go! You stink!
ひよりんもまた来てね
帰ろう　雪音君
Let us be off, my dear Yukine!
Come visit again, Hiyorin!
Of course!
Stop it!
やめろよ 離せって
はい
Let go!
あの　先の話ですが
いいんじゃねえか　いいんじゃねえか
Um, about what you said earlier...
キモいんだよ
Hm?
夜トが怖い神様って
When you said Yato's a scary god...
あれ冗談ですよね
That was just a joke, right?
本当よ
It's the truth.
夜トちゃん　昔神器を斬ったことがあるの
Yato-chan killed a Regalia a long time ago.
初めて夜トちゃんのこと知ったのも
The first time I heard about Yato-chan, it was from a nasty rumor.
悪いうわさからだったよ
Plus, since Yato-chan is a god of war...
それに夜トちゃんは武神でもあるから
he kills people too.
人斬りもするんだよ
人　斬り
He kills... people?
Quit it.
昔だ昔
That was a long time ago, back when it was all "kill or be killed."
斬るとか斬られるとかそんな時代だった頃の話
それってどういうことですか
What do you mean?
神って言うのは
Gods only exist to fulfill people's wishes.
人の願いがあってこそ存在できるんだ
名の知れた神は願われ慕われ続ける
Distinguished gods enjoy
constant worship and wishes.
だが　無名の神は違う
Lesser known gods don't have that luxury.
人の記憶にすらとどまることができねぇ
They can't even remain in people's memories.
忘れられないためにはどうするか
So what do you do so that
people will remember you?
願われたらなんでもする
You do whatever's asked of you...
so long as it's what someone wished for.
それが誰かの願いなら　なぁ
誰かの願い
What someone wished for...
長かったな
You stayed there for quite some time.
What were you talking about?
何話してた
夜ト　何で小福さんんとこに私を連れてきたの
Yato.
Why did you bring me to see Kofuku-san?
もし　俺に何かあったら
Listen...
If anything happens to me,
go straight to those two.
あの二人のところに行け
Okay?
いいな
え　うん
G-Got it!
He...
なんて　なんていい香り
He smells so nice!
何だって俺が見初めたやつだから
There's a reason I fell for him at first sight!
My, you have nice eyes.
君　綺麗な目してんだね
何しに来た　野良
What do you want, Nora?!
いやだ　ちゃんと名前で呼んで
No, no. Call me by my name.
私　夜トがつけてくれた名前　大好きよ
I love the name you gave me, Yato.
も　もしかして
D-Don't tell me she's...
この子も　夜トの神器
Is she your Regalia too?!
私はいつでも待ってるよ
I'll always be waiting...
夜トがあたしの名前　呼んでくれるのを
Waiting for you to call my name.
ki
mi
no
na
ma
e
na
ni
ga
a
tte
mo
ka
na
ra
zu
yo
bu
ka
ra
Whatever happens I will surely call out your name
君の名前 何があっても
必ず呼ぶから
ki
mi
wa
gi
za
ha
a
to
no
mo
chi
nu
shi
Your heart is all jagged
君はぎざぎざハートの持ち主
fu
re
ru
mo
no
wa
na
n
de
mo
ki
zu
tsu
ke
ru
So you hurt anything you touch
触れるものは何でも傷つけ
se
ka
i
no
su
be
te
wo
ni
ra
mi
tsu
ke
te
Those eyes that frown at everything
世界のすべてを睨み付けて
so
no
me
wa
i
un
da
bo
ku
wa
ko
ni
iru
They are saying "I'm here! See me!"
その目は言うんだ
「僕はここにいる」
da
re
ka
ga
wa
ra
tte
ta
Someone was laughing at you
誰かが笑ってた
da
ka
ra
hi
i
tan
da
so
no
kyo
u
ka
i
sen
So you put that barrier around you
だから引いたんだ その境界線
so
re
na
ra
wa
ta
shi
ga
so
no
te
wo
hi
ku
But I'll reach in there with my hand
それなら
私はその手を引く
さぁ
tsu
re
te
ku
ka
ra
And bring you out
連れてくから
i
e
na
i
ra
ko
no
te
wo
tsu
yo
ku
ni
gi
tte
If you don't have words, just grasp my hand
言えないなら
この手を強く握って
ha
na
sa
i
de
And don't let go
離さないで
ki
mi
wa
mo
u
hi
to
ri
ja
na
i
n
da
tte
I want you to know that you
君はもう一人じゃないんだって
知ってほしいんだよ
shi
tte
ho
shi
in
da
yo
Are not alone any more
小福　夜トって十回言ってみ
Hey, Kofuku. Say "Yato" ten times fast.
Yato, Yato, Yato, Yato, Yato, Yato, Yato, Yato, Yato, Yato!
夜ト夜ト夜ト夜ト夜ト夜ト夜ト夜ト夜ト夜ト
Who's the coolest guy in the world?
この世で一番かっこいいのは
Daikoku!
大黒
Who's the toughest god in the world?
この世で一番強い神は
あたし
Me!
Damn...
On the next Noragami: "Borderline."
次回　ノラガミ
Next Episode
Borderline
境界線